<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: DIY | Zigang Xiao]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ivansiu.com/blog/categories/diy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ivansiu.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-28T22:00:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ivansiu.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zigang Xiao (Ivan)]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fix Mid 2009 MBP RAM not recognized issue]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ivansiu.com/blog/2014/05/28/fix-mid-2009-mbp-ram-not-recognized-issue/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-28T23:30:56-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ivansiu.com/blog/2014/05/28/fix-mid-2009-mbp-ram-not-recognized-issue</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[![Possible cause of unrecoganized RAM](https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/3315210/blog/fix-mbp/mbp09-ram-theory.png)

A few days ago, I encountered an issue which seems to be common among mid-2009
MBPs: one of the RAM (in slot 1) is not recognized anymore. Or, sometimes
it is recognized, but after sleep and wake up, the computer freezes and
impossible to recover but force power off.

<!-- more -->

It turns out this is a common issue in this model. See the discussion in
this [thread](https://discussions.apple.com/message/25788934?ac_cid=tw123456#25788934) and this [thread](https://discussions.apple.com/thread/4263981?start=30&tstart=0). In the following, I am going to
present my temporary fix for this problem. 
For those of you that still want to stick to the old MBP, the fix shall last for
a while. But I do recomend you backup all the files and prepare to migrate some
day soon.

As I suggested in [my reply](https://discussions.apple.com/message/24868689#24868689), this may due to
a RAM slot degradation. My guess is, the RAM slot cannot align the RAM to a
correct contact positions any more. Precisely, see the post image above. Notice
that the two clips on the left and right are used to hold the rams in a
horizontal position, otherwise they will bend upwards. I took a close look at
those clips and found that the plastic wore out and cannot hold them as
original. I don't have great ways to fix them, so I just cropped some papers and
insert them between the RAMs and the back edges on the body, hoping they can
help tucking the RAMs.

As I am fixing it, I accidentally broke the left holder. So I have to customized
a plastic holder and stuck it with the logic board to hold the inner ram (slot 1).

![](https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/3315210/blog/fix-mbp/cracked-holder.jpg)

To verify my theory, I then taped a padding at the corresponding RAM position in the back cover:

![](https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/3315210/blog/fix-mbp/padding.jpg)

And they look like the following before I close:

![](https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/3315210/blog/fix-mbp/padding-ram.jpg)

Note that you have to screw it real tight to create the pressure such that
the RAM is aligned. That said, there will be a 'bump' at that position, 
and will easily cause scratch. So I use an apple sticker to cover my ass:

![](https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/3315210/blog/fix-mbp/sticker.jpg)

This method worked for me, well, at 99% of the time. Sometimes after sleep, the
MBP still won't wake up. I notice that this usually due to running  the MBP for
a long time, and it's hot inside. Nevertheless, this is the best solution I can
come up with by now. *If you have any other cheap solution that does not require
replacing the logic board, please let me know in the comments.*

Finally, Zach Clawson created a [dedicated page](https://people.cam.cornell.edu/~zc227/extras/mid2009mbp_RAM.html) for this issue, which 
lists lots of reference and provides explanation to it. Make sure you check it
out if you have encountered similar issue.

----

There are other common issues for this model, and they can be easily fixed. See
my following posts:

- [Fix frayed Magsafe cable](/blog/2013/11/08/saving-80-dollars-by-fixing-magsafe-by-yourself/)
- [Replace faulty SATA cable](/blog/2014/05/28/replacing-sata-cable-in-mid-2009-mbp/)

*If you have similar experience, do not hesitate to let me know. If you find my
instruction helpful, leave a comment and share it!*]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Replacing SATA cable in Mid 2009 MBP]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ivansiu.com/blog/2014/05/28/replacing-sata-cable-in-mid-2009-mbp/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-28T02:15:08-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ivansiu.com/blog/2014/05/28/replacing-sata-cable-in-mid-2009-mbp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[![Replacing MBP cable](https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/3315210/blog/fix-mbp/sata-cable.jpg)

Recently, my mid 2009 MBP (Model A1278) fails to recognize the hard drive. My
first bet was  another disk failure on me, but it was not the case. I took down
the hard drive and put it to a mobile hard drive case and it can be read
smoothly.

<!-- more -->

It turns out that it is due to the SATA cable fault, which is 
a notorious problem for mid 2009 MBP model. See
the threads and discussions 
[here](http://forums.macrumors.com/showthread.php?t=1031577),
[here](http://www.ifixit.com/Answers/View/36360/Internal+hard+drive+disk+not+recognized),
[here](http://www.ifixit.com/Answers/View/43072/Hard+Drive+not+recognized+by+system+during+boot+or+install)
and [here](https://discussions.apple.com/message/25454809#25454809).

Luckily, the solution is simple, just go ahead and purchase 
a [replacement cable][cable ifixit] and replace it. iFixit has a very detailed
[illustrated document] on the procedures.
However, Amazon has a [cheaper option](cable amazon), and it works fine for me. I didn't test
the infra-red though, since I never and not plan to use it.

There are other common issues for this model, and they can be easily fixed. See
my following posts:

- [Fix frayed Magsafe cable](/blog/2013/11/08/saving-80-dollars-by-fixing-magsafe-by-yourself/)
- [Fix unrecognized RAM](/blog/2014/05/28/fix-mid-2009-mbp-ram-not-recognized-issue/)

*If you have similar experience, do not hesitate to let me know. If you find my
instruction helpful, leave a comment and share it!*

[cable ifixit]: http://www.ifixit.com/MacBook-Parts/MacBook-Pro-13-Inch-Unibody-Hard-Drive-Cable/IF163-013#productDescription
[illustrated document]: http://www.ifixit.com/Guide/MacBook+Pro+13-Inch+Unibody+Mid+2009+Hard+Drive+Cable+Replacement/1340
[cable amazon]: http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004VSZCL4/ref=oh_details_o02_s00_i00?ie=UTF8&psc=1]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saving $80 by Fixing MagSafe by Yourself]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ivansiu.com/blog/2013/11/08/saving-80-dollars-by-fixing-magsafe-by-yourself/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-08T22:06:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ivansiu.com/blog/2013/11/08/saving-80-dollars-by-fixing-magsafe-by-yourself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[After four years of use, the wire on my MagSafe finally fray out. After searching a bit, I found that a new one costs $80!!
My old memories came back: almost all accessories by Apple are rip-offs. See how low the ratings are:

![][ratings]

I know that this can be easily fixed if you know a little soldering and have courage: the adapter is working perfectly fine, it is just the wires.
I decided to DIY. There are several pretty good articles on how to [open the MagSafe][open] and how to [solder it][solder].

<!-- more -->

The following are my workflows. The first step is to open it. You can see there are two wires, in fact in my case only the black wire is broken.
I don't even need to solder.

-------------- -------------
 ![][wires1]    ![][wires2]
-------------- -------------

Okay, go ahead and twist them. Use insulating tapes to wrap them tight.

![][insulating]

Finally, reassemble it and use more tapes, since the outside layer is cut out. More importantly, strong taping help to protect another fray.

![][taping]

It looks a bit odd though, since the Apple product is supposed to be WHITE.
Here's how I fix it. I don't have good tools available, so I just use whatever
I have. I recalled that I have some Google stickers, and I just cut the white
pieces out.

![][stickers]

After more taping, it looks like better now. Maybe I should consider wrapping better things outside later.

![][wrap]

Hooray! Now it is working again! In fact, I am amazed that this piece of gadget has been working for four years, daily. It is still working just fine :)

There are other common issues for this model, and they can be easily fixed. See
my following posts:

- [Replace faulty SATA cable](/blog/2014/05/28/replacing-sata-cable-in-mid-2009-mbp/)
- [Fix unrecognized RAM](/blog/2014/05/28/fix-mid-2009-mbp-ram-not-recognized-issue/)

*If you have similar experience, do not hesitate to let me know. If you find my
instruction helpful, leave a comment and share it!*

[open]: http://www.instructables.com/id/How-to-open-and-replace-the-MagSafe-cord-on-an-App/?ALLSTEPS
[solder]: http://www.instructables.com/id/MacBook-Mag-Safe-Charger-Budget-Repair-Disas/
[ratings]: https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-HbwCGT5IRfg/Un22iAWR3FI/AAAAAAAA6S8/kb8A295sneA/s800/Apple%252085W%2520MagSafe%2520Power%2520Adapter%2520%2528for%252015-%2520and%252017-inch%2520MacBook%2520Pro%2529%2520-%2520Apple%2520Store%2520%2528U.S.%2529.png
[wires1]: https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-3YuxG4NzMls/Un23QYqlRvI/AAAAAAAA6TI/OHnqW_Mz3_M/s600/IMG_5533.jpg
[wires2]: https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-4Vwfhl0a7U0/Un23UWD3pII/AAAAAAAA6TY/32jW30GJiHo/s600/IMG_5534.jpg
[insulating]: https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-rInGpQS3MPA/Un23Utgk5pI/AAAAAAAA6Tc/XbpbDy2m4yo/s600/IMG_5535.jpg
[taping]: https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-GNyM8TlkwIA/Un23ZUE9GBI/AAAAAAAA6Tk/VUI9YF7zK_Y/s600/IMG_5536.jpg
[stickers]: https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-0-qhNqp4ClA/Un23fZLy24I/AAAAAAAA6T4/7MTAsUReDLw/s600/IMG_5537.JPG
[wrap]: https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Ok8Zop2yeFY/Un23fsZ_1VI/AAAAAAAA6UU/njomi434w70/s600/IMG_5538.jpg
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing a new car stereo]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ivansiu.com/blog/2013/08/30/installing-a-new-car-stereo/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-30T16:50:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ivansiu.com/blog/2013/08/30/installing-a-new-car-stereo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[I did not realize until my car's radio's broken that, with less than a hundred bucks, you can buy a new Head Unit with nearly all functionality. Some note-worthy features include:

- iPod/iPhone support. Control the iphone directly from the panel.
- App support. This includes I-heart-radio, pandora, etc.
- Bluetooth Audio: stream music directly from a paired device. Even supports Pandora!
- Upgraded FM/AM support. Displays text from radio stations.

 <!-- more -->

Since I never used CD, I actually decided to buy a Digital Media Receiver: [JVC KD-X250BT](http://www.crutchfield.com/S-kT2jsjodqXG/p_105KDX250B/JVC-KD-X250BT.html). Since every car has a different wiring harness, we need to buy a compatible wiring harness. My car has a Double DIN design but the DMR is a single DIN one, so I actually need to buy a installation kit. The wiring setup is fun:

<img class="left" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-zOOgWaP5-W8/UiETJQhmUVI/AAAAAAAA6AM/jRAo6LHRlDU/s400/IMG_5341.jpg">
<img class="right" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-n_QzAv5VgfQ/UiETKOBShuI/AAAAAAAA6AU/_F3-gN-NDio/s400/IMG_5342.jpg">
<img class="left" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-p7tlzn7kbRc/UiETKzbUaCI/AAAAAAAA6Ac/37Dgx3cbUJM/s400/IMG_5344.jpg">

<img class="right" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-KJRCnhX64lg/UiETLxnhJKI/AAAAAAAA6Ak/qdqbEPUfAUI/s600/IMG_5345.JPG">
<img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-h0tu6PrFzIk/UiETMWNKURI/AAAAAAAA6As/Zll5LFDkixM/s600/IMG_5346.JPG">
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
