<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: insurance | Ivan's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.ivansiu.com/blog/categories/insurance/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.ivansiu.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-09-03T13:29:38-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.ivansiu.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zigang "Ivan" Xiao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making an Comprehensive Insurance Claim After Got Hit by Road Debris (Flying Object)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.ivansiu.com/blog/2017/04/30/making-an-comprehensive-insurance-claim-after-got-hit-by-road-debris-flying-object/"/>
    <updated>2017-04-30T13:30:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.ivansiu.com/blog/2017/04/30/making-an-comprehensive-insurance-claim-after-got-hit-by-road-debris-flying-object</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[Just a normal day of going to work. Bang! I got hit by a flying object ... :(

<!-- more -->


## How it happened
This video best explains it:

<video  preload='metadata' controls ><source src='http://res.cloudinary.com/maomao/video/upload/v1493584125/blog/flying_debris.mp4' type='video/mp4; codecs="avc1.42E01E, mp4a.40.2"'></video>


## Getting a quote
While I am pretty sure that this should be a comprehensive claim, I wanted to avoid it if this can be repaired under a few hundred dollars.
The common saying is that comprehensive claim will not increase your premimum, but there is also saying in the web that said if you *claim three times in a three year period*, it might. I went ahead to get quote from two shops, and turned out that it is way more than I expected: they range from \\$1800 to \\$2200!.

First, let's take a look at my damanges:

![](https://res.cloudinary.com/maomao/image/upload/w_400/v1493586583/scratch1.jpg)
![](https://res.cloudinary.com/maomao/image/upload/w_400/v1493585253/scratch2.jpg)
![](https://res.cloudinary.com/maomao/image/upload/w_400/v1493585253/scratch3.jpg)

The scratches are all over, and the most severe one, as shown in the first image, is that my base layer seems to be damaged.

![](https://res.cloudinary.com/maomao/image/upload/v1493585408/car_paint_layers.png)

Depending on different level of damage on the layers, including base, prime, base (paint) and clear coat layer, this is the hardest one so it actually takes quite a lot money to fix. For a simple clear coat damage, it is easy enough to DIY, and I've found some awesome tutorials online, including [this](http://guidetodetailing.com/damage-repair/how-to-repair-paint-chips-deep-scratches/) and [this](http://www.carpaintrepairinfo.com/repair-deep-car-scratches-50/). There are also a bunch of videos online.

Unfortunately my problem is way over that, and I guess I do have to make a claim. I do need to pay \\$500 deductible, so the insurance will actually pay \\$2k-ish minus deductible. The good thing is that while my car is being fixed, I still got a ride from Hertz, paid by my insurance company.

## Making a claim
Making a claim is easy. Just called the number and make the case. A case number will be created and an insurance adjuster will be assigned. After discussing with the adjuster, I can take the car to the body shop and an appraiser will come and do an inspection.

## Getting the paint repaired


## Conclusion
My overall experience with comprehensive insurance has been very good. I have claimed it a few times to repair not-at-fault damages, and in fact it already paid off my insurance premimums paid these years... However, I do have to pay deductible per-case basis, which is non-trivial also (except glass claim). Getting a zero-deductible claim will increase the premium a lot, so it seems 500 deductible is the norm.
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
